Charles Ives Rare and Non-Commercial Sound Recordings
Yale University Music Library
Charles Ives Rare and Non-Commercial Sound Recordings
1924-2006
1937-1956
MSS 14 HSR
Yale University Music Library
15
30 boxes; 440 sound recordings
Ives, Charles, 1874-1954
Scope and Contents
This is an artificial collection of rare and unpublished recordings featuring music by Charles Ives, created as part of a project funded by the Grammy Museum in 2017 to digitize and preserve these recordings.
The majority of the recordings were unprocessed materials within Historical Sound Recordings (HSR) that had been acquired over time through various donations. These recordings were pulled from their storage locations (predominantly ML 102M, HSR Studio and B20B Basement) into this artificial collection. However, a number of recordings were also pulled from boxes 74, 75, 76, 80, 82, and 83 of The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93), a collection that was only minimally processed at the time this artificial collection was created. Notes have been added to the aforementioned boxes from the Boatwright Collection, in addition to the relevant item records in this finding aid, detailing this decision and ensuring the original provenance of these items is well documented.
Finally, a small number of items included in this finding aid, that were also part of the digitization project funded by the Grammy Museum in 2017, are in fact part of different collections, namely the Richard C. Burns Archive of Overtone Records (MSS 104) and Yale School of Music Tapes (HSR 4). The Richard C. Burns Archive of Overtone Records collection is fully processed. However, the finding aid for the collection currently only exists in paper form. It was decided that these materials should be included in this artificial collection in order to improve access, but that if and when the finding aid for the Richard C. Burns Archive of Overtone Records collection was added to ArchivesSpace, these items would be removed from this artificial collection. The Yale School of Music Tapes are technically on deposit with the Gilmore Music Library. The Yale School of Music maintains documentation on the location of each recording in the collection. However, no finding aid exists for the collection. It was decided that these materials should therefore remain in their existing collection but again be included in this finding aid to improve access.
Access
The majority of the materials in this collection have been digitized and are available to stream online. However, with the exception of recordings of John Kirkpatrick performing Ives' Concord Sonata highlighted below, for which Yale University Library has obtained the necessary permissions to stream without restriction, all other materials are only available when connected to the Yale network, either onsite at Yale or via the Yale VPN.
The following recordings of Ives's Piano Sonata No.2, "Concord, Mass, 1840-1860," performed by John Kirkpatrick, are available to stream to the public, regardless of access location. As the various parts of these performances are spread across multiple items in the collection, the following playlists are available for each performance:
1939-01-20: World Premiere, New York Town Hall. Complete performance. Includes encore of last movement.
1939-03-24: CBS Music Hour, Keyboard Concerts, WABC. Emerson and Alcotts only.
1939-03-31: CBS Music Hour, Keyboard Concerts, WABC. Hawthorne and Thoreau only.
1939-09-28: First complete radio broadcast. Composers Forum, WNYC.
1959-10-19: Emerson only.
1969-02-07: Complete recording. Sprague Memorial Hall, Yale University.
Related Collection
MSS 14, The Charles Ives Papers.
Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Sonatas (Piano); Ives, Charles, 1874-1954; Kirkpatrick, John, 1905-1991; Boatwright, Helen
- Audiocassettes, Series I
  - Concord Sonata, 1980; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038373297)
    Scope and Contents
    Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano.
  - Dubs of various songs and poems for Ted Stein, 1977 February 8; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038372091)
  - Vern Nelson performs Charles Ives, Waltz, at 1989 recital in Silliman College, 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038372000)
    Performers: Vern Nelson.
  - Poets in Cornwall, undated; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038372018)
    Performers: John Barber of St. Ives. Upon review following digitization, this item was found to not contain any music by Charles Ives.
  - Charles Ives at Ursinus College, undated; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038373479)
  - Bolcom: Black Max -- Bolcom: Hist Whist -- Ives: Grantchester, 1998 November; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038373487)
    Performers: Howard Boatwright.
  - 24 songs, undated; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002126011163)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright and John Kirkpatrick.
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93), Box 82 - June 2017
  - Ives; Bacon; songs, undated; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002126011171)
  - Saint David's Celebration; Art program; Ives; Bolcom, 1995 May 6; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002126011189)
  - Ives: Greatest Man -- At the River -- Circus Band -- Schoenberg: Pierrot Lunaire, undated; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002126011197)
    Performers: Cleo Lane?
    Pulled from The Howard and Helen Boatwright papers (MSS 93), Box 83 - June 2017
  - Ives Concord Sonata, 1969 February 7; 1 (Box 117, Item barcode 39002038372679)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick.Sprague Memorial Hall, Yale University.
  - Ives: Central Park in the Dark -- Unanswered Question, undated; 1 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002038372315)
    This item is part of of a separate collection - HSR YSM Recordings
  - Ives Project: Samples, undated; 1 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002038372331)
- Compact discs, Series II
  - Slow March -- Down East, 2006 November 18; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002128474591)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright, soprano; Steven Heyman, piano. Helen Boatwright: 90th Birthday Celebration.
  - Piano Sonata No. 3, 1998 December 11; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373438)
    Performers: Peter Geisselbrecht, piano.
  - Charles Ives Society Panel Discussion: Indiana University: Working with John Kirkpatrick, 2001 October 26; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373446)
  - Ives 2nd, undated; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373453)
  - Ives Song Recital, 1969 November 2; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373461)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright and John Kirkpatrick. Crouse Auditorium.
  - CDR 238 F: John Kirkpatrick recital. Dubbed from acetates, 1968 July 29; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372752)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick.
  - CDR 239 F: Tunes that Charles Ives used in his orchestral works, 2006 March 24; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372745)
    Performers: Paul Woodiel.
  - CDR 240 F: Tunes that Charles Ives used in his Orchestral Works: Tracks 1-17, 2005 December 5; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372760)
    Performers: Paul Berry, tenor; Alexis Zingale, piano.
  - Symphony no. 3; Carnegie Hall Recording Co., 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373495)
    Performers: CBS Symphony Orchestra; Bernard Herrmann (conductor).
  - Helen Boatwright: Charles Ives Masterclass: 1, 2002 March 21; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372711)
    Helen Boatwright.
  - TCU Ives Lecture, 2003 January 22; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372729)
  - TCU: Ives Festival Concert, 2003 January 22; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372737)
  - Symphony No. 4, 1970 February 20; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372786)
    Performers: Yale Symphony Orchestra; John Mauceri, conductor; Yale Bach Society; Paul Althouse, conductor; John Kirkpatrick, piano.
  - Ives: Two Contemplations -- Milhaud: Le Boeuf sur le Toit -- Debussy: Jeux, 1968 December 15; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372778)
    Performers: Yale Symphony Orchestra; John Mauceri, conductor.
  - Haydn: Sinfonie Concertante -- Ives: Thanksgiving and Forefather's Day, 1959 November 24; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038371804)
    Performers: New Haven Symphony Orchestra; Frank Brieff, conductor.
  - Haydn; Ives, 1959 November 24; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038373503)
    Performers: New Haven Symphony Orchestra.
  - Ives: Two Contemplations -- Milhaud: Le Bouef sur le Toit -- Debussy: Jeux, 1968 December 15; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372836)
  - Symphony No.4, 1970 February 20; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372794)
  - Charles Ives, 1974 February 9; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372844)
  - Ives, 1975 October 29; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372810)
    Performers: Yale Symphony Orchestra; C. William Harwood, conductor.
  - Variations on America -- A New England Symphony, 1974 February 9; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372802)
  - Chadwick: Jubilee -- Ives: Yale-Princeton Game -- Wyner: Concerto da Camera -- Carl: Raptures -- Ruggles: Sun-treader, 1976 February 14; 1 (Box 107, Item barcode 39002038372828)
- DAT tapes, Series III
  - Master A, 2004 April 17; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002038372588)
    Performers: Yves Dharamraj, cello.
    This item is part of of a separate collection - HSR YSM Recordings Collection. After review of this material following digitization, it was found to not contain any works by Charles Ives.
- DTRS tapes, Series IV
  - Ives E safety 1, 2005 May 13; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372349)
    This item is part of of a separate collection - HSR YSM Recordings Collection
  - Ives safety 1, 2005 May 11; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372356)
  - Ives safety 1, 2005 May 12; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372364)
  - Ives safety 1 F, 2005 May 17; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372372)
  - Ives safety 2, 2005 May 11; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372380)
  - Ives safety 2, 2005 May 12; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372562)
  - Ives session D safety 1, 2005 May 13; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372398)
  - Ives session D safety 2, 2005 May 13; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372406)
  - Ives session E safety 2, 2005 May 13; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372414)
  - Ives session F safety 2, 2005 May 17; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372422)
  - Ives Session H safety 1, 2005 May 19; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372448)
  - Ives Session H safety 2, 2005 May 19; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372430)
  - Ives Session I safety 1, 2005 May 20; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372463)
  - Ives session I safety 2, 2005 May 20; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372471)
  - Ives session J safety 1, 2005 May 24; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372489)
  - Ives session J safety 2, 2005 May 24; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372497)
  - Ives take A1-B20 safety 2, 2005 May 9; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372547)
  - Ives take A1-B20: master 2, 2005 May 9; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372554)
  - Ives tape G safety 1, 2005 May 18; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372505)
  - Ives tape G safety 2, 2005 May 18; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372513)
  - Ives tape K safety 1, 2005 May 25; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372521)
  - Ives tape K safety 2, 2005 May 25; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002038372539)
- Instantaneous discs, Series V; All discs in this series are 12 inch lacquer discs, except where noted.
  - 1st String Quartet -- 4th Symphony, 1943 March 17; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371788)
    Performers: Concert Orchestra.
  - Ann Street -- Greatest Man -- The Two Little Flowers -- Parts 2 and 4, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371267)
    American Music Festival.
  - Ann Street -- Greatest Man -- Two Little Flowers; American Music Festival; Part 4, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371275)
  - American Music Festival; Part 7, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371432)
  - American Music Festival; Parts 5 and 7, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371424)
  - American Music Festival; Parts 6 and 8, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371291)
  - Charlie Rutlage -- Evening, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371283)
  - Evening -- Charlie Rutlage -- Parts 1 and 3, 1940 February 12; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372323)
  - Barn Dance from Washington's Birthday, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371317)
  - Layo for Strings -- Hymn -- March -- Quick Step, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371465)
  - Symphony No. 3, 2nd Movement; Part 1, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371770)
    Performers: CBS Symphony Orchestra; Bernard Herrman, conductor; Invitation for Music.
  - Concert Orchestra performance, 1943 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371473)
  - Concert Orchestra performance, 1943 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371481)
  - Concert Orchestra performance, 1943 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371499)
  - Frederick Fennell performance, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371796)
    Performers: Frederick Fennell; WABC. Possible date on label of November 11th, but year not noted.
  - Goodnight Ladies -- Barn Dance from Washington's Birthday, 1943 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371374)
    Performers: Columbia Concert Orchestra; Bernard Herrman, conductor.
  - Berceuse -- World's Highway -- The Sideshow; Parts 1 and 2, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371572)
    Composers Forum.
  - Night Song -- At the River -- Mists -- On the Counter; Parts 3 and 4, undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371564)
  - Symphony No. 4, 3rd Movement (Fugue) -- 1st String Quartet, 1943 March 17; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371507)
  - Symphony No. 4, Prelude and Fugue -- 1st String Quartet, 1943 March 17; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371515)
  - Concord Piano Sonata,1st and 2nd Movement; Parts 7 and 8, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371549)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick. Composers Forum, WNYC.
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 1st Movement; Parts 5 and 6, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371556)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 2nd and 3rd Movements; Parts 9 and 10, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371531)
  - Concord Piano Sonata, 3rd and 4th Movement; Parts 11 and 12, 1939 September 28; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371523)
  - Emerson Part 3 -- The Things Our Father Loved Part 2 -- General Booth Enters into Heaven Part 2, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371622)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick, Mina Hager.
  - Evening -- Downeast -- Thoreau Part 2, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371648)
  - Symphony No. 4, 3rd Movement; Fugue, 1942 April 13; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371218)
  - Symphony No. 2, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371051)
    Contains commentaries by James Fassett of C.A.S.
  - Symphony No. 3, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371358)
  - Beethoven: Sonata Op. 53, Part 5 Side 5 -- Ives: Thoreau, Part 3 Side 15, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371721)
  - Beethoven: Sonata Op. 53, Side 4 -- Ives: Thoreau, Side 14, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371739)
  - Beethoven: Sonata Op. 53, Side 3 -- Ives: The Alcotts, Side 13, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371762)
  - Beethoven Sonata Op.53, Side 2 -- Ives: The Alcotts, Side 12, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371747)
  - Ives: Emerson, Part 1 -- Beethoven: Bagatelle in G, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371713)
  - Ives: Emerson, Part 4 -- Ives: Hawthorne, Part 1 -- Chopin: Etude in A Flat, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371689)
  - Ives: Emerson, Part 2 -- Fugue Part 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371705)
  - Ives: Emerson, Part 3 -- Fugue, Part 2 -- Chopin: Valse in A Flat, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371697)
  - Beethoven: Sonata Op.53 - Side 1, Ives: Hawthorne -- Thoreau, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371754)
  - Emerson, Part 2, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371614)
  - Autumn, Part 1 -- Hawthorne -- Alcotts, Part 3, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371663)
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Part 10, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371168)
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Part 11, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371101)
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Part 12, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371119)
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Parts 3 and 5, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371127)
    Performers: John Kirkpatrick. CBS Music Hour - Keyboard Concerts, WABC.
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Parts 2 and 4, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371135)
  - Concord Massachusetts Sonata; Parts 1 and 6, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371150)
  - In the Cage -- In the Night; Dub, 1941 November 11; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038372455)
    Performers: Frederick Fennell; Milestones in American Music.
  - Emerson, Part 1 -- At the River -- Berceuse, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371606)
  - Fugue -- Hawthrone, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371671)
  - Autumn, Part 2 -- Alcotts, Part 2 -- Thoreau Part 1, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371655)
  - Booth, Part 1 -- Hawthorne, Part 1, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371630)
  - Downeast -- Thoreau, Part 3, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371598)
  - String Quartet in G, Part 1 of 3, 1943 March 16; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371176)
    Performers: College Concert Orchestra.
  - Sonata No. 2 for violin and piano -- Largo for violin, clarinet, and piano, 1956 February 22; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371457)
    Performers: Howard Boatwright, violin; Keith Wilson, clarinet; Donald Currier, piano.
  - Symphony No. 3, 1956 February 22; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371440)
    Performers: The University Orchestra; Howard Boatwright, conductor; Helen Boatwright, John Kirkpatrick.
  - Piano Sonata, Part I; Dub, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371143)
  - Piano Sonata, Part 6, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371077)
  - Piano Sonata, Part 2; Dub, 1939 March 24; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371093)
  - Piano Sonata, Parts 2 and 4, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371184)
  - Piano Sonata, Parts 1 and 3, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371085)
  - Piano Sonata by Charles Ives; WABC; Part 5; 3/31/39, 1939 March 31; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371069)
  - Quartet in G Major, Part 2, 1937 May 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371325)
    WABC Copy.
  - Quartet in G Major, 1937 May 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371333)
  - Symphony No. 2; Side 3 and 4, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371242)
  - Psalm 67, 1948 September 13; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371341)
    Performers: The Robert Shaw Chorale.
  - Sonata No. 3 Piano and Violin, Allegro, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371234)
    Performers: Carol Robinson, piano; Madeleine Carabo, violin.
  - Sonata No. 3 Piano and Violin, Adagio; Pts 1 and 3, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371259)
  - Symphony No. 3, 2nd Movement; Part 3, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371416)
    Performers: CBS Symphony; Bernard Herrman, conductor. Invitation to Music.
  - Symphony No. 3; Part 1, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371382)
  - Symphony No. 2, 1956 May 9; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371309)
    Performers: London Symphony Orchestra; Bernard Herrman, conductor.
  - Symphony No. 3, 1st Movement; Part 1, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371390)
    Performers: CBS Symphony Orchestra; Bernard Herrmann, conductor.
  - Symphony No.3; Charles Ives; 3rd Movement; Invitation to Music; CBS Symphony; Bernard Herrman; 9/11/46, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371408)
  - The Greatest Man, 1939 February 24; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038371580)
  - The Largo for Strings, 1938 March 14; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371200)
  - Ives: Symphony No. 3 -- Ben Weber: Pieces for Strings -- Robert Evett: Concerto for Small Orchestra, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371366)
    Performers: The Yaddo Orchestra; Frederick Fennell, conductor.
  - Strauss: Moto Perpetuo -- Ives: Washington's Birthday, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038371192)
    Performers: Cape Cod Symphony Society; Jo Hawthorne, conductor.
  - Beethoven: Sonata op. 53, part 1 -- Ives: 1840, Hawthorne, part 3, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370392)
    Scope and Content
  - Beethoven: Sonata op. 53, part 3 -- Ives: 1840, The Alcotts, part 2 -- Thoreau, part 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370376)
  - Beethoven: Sonata op. 53, part 4 -- Ives 1840, Thoreau, part 2, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370343)
  - Beethoven: Sonata op. 53, part 5 -- Ives: 1840, Thoreau, part 3, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370335)
  - Beethoven: Sonata op. 53, part 2 -- Ives: 1840, The Alcotts, part 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370384)
  - Beethoven: sonata op. 58 -- Ives: 1840, Hawthorne, part 3, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370434)
  - Chopin: Grande Valse op. 42 -- Ives: 1840, Emerson, part 3, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370418)
  - Ives: 1840, Emerson, part 1 -- Beethoven: Bagatelle in G, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370327)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 1 -- Beethoven: Bagatelle in G, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370442)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 2 -- Ives: Fugue on theme "From Greenland's Icy Mountain" (arr. Kirkpatrick), 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370426)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 2 -- Ives: Fugue on theme "From Greenland's Icy Mountains" (arr. Kirkpatrick), 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370293)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 3 -- Chopin: Grande Valse op. 42, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370301)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 4 -- Hawthorne, part 1 -- Chopin: Etude in A Flat op. 25 no. 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370319)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Emerson, part 4 -- Hawthorne, part 1 -- Chopin: Etude op. 25 no. 1, 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370400)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Hawthorne, part 2 -- Anon (French XIII): La Septime Estampie Royale (unison), 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370350)
  - Ives: Concord 1840, Hawthorne, part 2 -- Anon (French XIII) La Septime Estampie Royale (Unison), 1939 January 20; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370368)
  - Decoration Day, 1966 April 17; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370475)
    Performers: Cornell Symphony Orchestra.
  - Quartet in G, 2nd movement; Parts 1 and 2, 1939 July 29; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370467)
    Performers: Dorian String Quartet.
  - Quartet in G, 1st Movement; Parts 1 and 2; Copy, 1939 July 22; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370459)
    Performer: Dorian String Quartet.
  - Symphony No. 3, 1st Movement, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370483)
    Bernard Herrmann, conductor.
  - Symphony No. 3, 2nd Movement, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370491)
  - Symphony No. 3, 3rd Movement, 1946 September 11; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038370509)
  - The London Recordings, undated; 1 (Box 108, Item barcode 39002038373792)
    Disc No. (?): TT-1419-1; TT-1419-2.
  - Charles Ives #32162 [no title given], undated; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038374147)
    for Leroy[?] Parkins.
  - Ives Songs, Disc 2, 1970 September 9; 1 (Box 109, Item barcode 39002038373412)
    Performers: Helen Boatwright, John Kirkpatrick.